# MARAT FAKHREEV

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Kazan, Russia +7 (951) 891-72-33

maratfakhreev.com github.com/maratfakhreev linkedin.com/in/maratfakhreev medium.com/@maratfakhreev marat.fakhreev@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

I'm front-end engineer with more than 5 years experience. I like CSS and Javascript (recently have added Typescript into my arsenal), like writing both useful and not too much code in my free time. I'm a big fan of open source projects. Sometimes I work with Node.js and Ruby/Rails. Take a moment to explore crazy stuff from the web world.

## **EXPERIENCE**

FRONT-END LEAD ENGINEER, REVEALBOT, USA, 2018-PRESENT I've responsible for client part of huge distributed application that provides convenient tools that automate ad management strategies for popular ad platforms such Facebook/Google etc. Core technologies are Vue, Vuex, JSX, Styled-components, Webpacker, Ruby on Rails.

FRONT-END ENGINEER, CINARRA SYSTEMS, RUSSIA, 2017-2018 I've responsible for front-end part of huge RTB application. This part allows clients to form an advertising company, specify the target audience and also monitor its effectiveness on the basis of multiple metrics. Core technologies are React, Redux, Recompose and other FP stuff.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/LEAD DEVELOPER, FLATSTACK, RUSSIA, 2013-2017 I was responsible for front-end part of different projects with different complexity and field of activity. Here at different time I was a part of 3-10 people size teams which provide full development cycle. I've tried popular FE-frameworks like React, Angular, Backbone/Marionette, also gained experience in varying degrees with technologies such as Node.js on BE, Cordova/Phonegap as mobile framework.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, DARING AND YOUNG, RUSSIA, 2012-2013 I was responsible for front-end work of websites. Most projects were on Backbone.js and jQuery. Was mostly focused on markup.

#### **EDUCATION**

2013-2015 Russia, Kazan State University. Master's degree in computer science. 2009-2013 Russia, Kazan State University. Bachelor's degree in computer science.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3/Pre-Post processors/Styled components, JavaScript, ES6, Typescript, CoffeeScript, React, Flux/Redux, Vue, Vuex, Backbone/Marionette, Webpack/ Browserify/Gulp/Grunt, Cordova, React Native, Electron, Node.js, REST, JSON-API, Functional Programming, OOP, MVC, Unidirectional architectures, Messenger bots.

## **OPEN SOURCE**

React-base, http://github.com/fs/react-base

React hot loader, https://github.com/gaearon/react-hot-loader

Marionette.js, https://github.com/marionettejs/backbone.marionette

React Native Starter Kit, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/react-native-starter-kit

Backbone-base, http://github.com/fs/backbone-base

Backbone ES6 Promise, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/backbone-es6-promise Marionette Animated Region, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-animated-

<u>region</u>

Marionette Routes Helper, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-routes-helper Node telegram random message replier, https://github.com/maratfakhreev/nodetelegram-random-message-replier

## PET PROJECTS

# DailySheet, daily-dev.com

<u>About</u>: Desktop application that accumulates useful feeds. Keeping you in touch with the latest news on technology. Whether you are a developer, manager, designer or just a cat lover like us, there is something to catch your eye or mind.

Role: Client app Developer, Website Front-end Developer.

<u>Stack</u>: Electron, Typescript, React (with hooks)/Redux, Styled components, Webpack, Ansible, vscale.io.

# Stockroom, stockroom-dev.herokuapp.com

<u>About</u>: Service for accounting some goods via QR-codes. Primarily focused on owners of warehouses, stores and even offices that want to count their things.

Role: Front-end Developer.

Stack: React-on-Rails, Webpack, Rails, Heroku.